BK

Brian Kilpatrick

Professional Summary

Determined and solution-driven Software Developer (MERN), with a background in management, procurement, and analytics. A focus set on meeting the highest standards, user experience, scalability, and total client satisfaction. Experienced creating websites and web applications with technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, C#, React, AWS, MySQL, MongoDB, and Ruby.

Work History

U2 Education - Coding Teaching Assistant

Richmond, VA

06/2020 - Current

Assisted in teaching the University of Richmond Coding Boot Camp

Self Employed - Freelance Web Developer

Richmond, VA

05/2020 - Current

- Used various technologies, including React, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Mongo, and MySQL to make code repairs, and optimized websites for various clients.
- Re-designed existing websites for search engine optimization and responsiveness.

Delaware North - Multi-Unit Manager

Richmond, VA

06/2018 - Current

- Create PO's for the procurement of product that supplies nine total units. This product includes all F&B, paper product, and janitorial supplies
- Manages staff while withholding company policy, standards, and expectations
- Ensures a timely delivery of product through a requisitioning process from the commissary kitchen to each unit
- Review monthly inventory, which includes price updates, inputting of invoices, and inputting of sales and costs
- Create weekly waste reports to find issues with pars, misuse, or over-requisitioning. Create process improvements to limit the above

TheBrianKilpatrick@gmail.com (804) 839-3418 Richmond, VA 23225

- https://github.com/thebriankilpatrick
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/thebriankilpatrick/
- https://thebriankilpatrick.github.io /portfolio/

Skills

- HTML5
- CSS
- Bootstrap / Materialize / UI Kit
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Git
- API's
- Node.js / Express / Handlebars
- MySQL / Sequelize / MongoDB / Mongoose
- AWS
- PWA's / IndexedDB
- React / Redux
- Ruby
- Java

Education

05/2020

University of Richmond

Richmond, VA

Certificate: Full Stack Coding Boot Camp

The Boathouse - FOH Manager

Richmond, VA

06/2015 - 06/2018

- Hired, trained, scheduled, and managed staff while withholding company policy, standards, and expectations. This also included external guest expectations and ensuring the deliverance of excellence in service
- Controlled BLW costs and managed inventory and procurement of product
- Accurately reported end-of-day sales, and calculated labor costs, food costs, and alcohol costs

Projects

Box Office Depot

Box Office Depot is a web application that utilizes multiple API's to display new and coming soon movies, movie theaters and show times, and allows the user to also search for theaters and movies. This was a group project that I worked on with three others.

https://krpharr.github.io/box-office-depot/index.html

Super Smash Kittens

Super Smash Kittens is an online battle card game, where you can chat and battle with other users in real time.

https://supersmashkittens.herokuapp.com/

Lorenzo's List

Lorenzo's List is a heroku deployed application that allows the user to view and post items for sale, as well as message other users to contact about their items. All of the users and items are stored in a SQL database. https://dry-meadow-42689.herokuapp.com/